# **SREE LAKSHMI SETTURU**

sreelakshmisetturu@gmail.com
https://www.linkedin.com/in/sreelakshmi-setturu

https://github.com/sreelakshmisetturu https://sreelakshmisetturu.github.io/

## **Professional Summary:**

Master's Degree in Computer science with one and two years of experience in application development and support.

 Possess solid understanding of Object Oriented Programming and Design and hands on experience in Big data processing technologies such as Hadoop Map Reduce and Apache Spark.

### **Skills:**

Programming languages: Java, Python, MySQL, JavaScript (ES6)

Big Data and Cloud Technologies: Apache Spark, Hadoop MapReduce

Web technologies: HTML, CSS, JSP, Servlets, Spring MVC

OS: Linux

Web Services: RESTful

## **Work Experience:**

### Software Engineer-I, Lexis Nexis Risk Solutions

Sept 2017-Present

- Migrated a large-scale web application from Struts 1 to **Spring MVC.**
- Identified and resolved issues related to concurrency and hibernate transaction.
- Automated regression testcases using Selenium Web-driver and TestNG. Performed regression testing on the same application.

### Assistant System Engineer (Java Developer), TATA Consultancy Services

Jun 2014-Dec 2015

- Designed and developed a web application, which is used by client staff to manage products and sales using JSP, Servlets & Hibernate ORM.
- Maintained large code base and Enhanced the functionality of a Java Web application. Made code fixes which stabilized the application and reduced the ticket count by 10%.

### **Education:**

Masters in Computer science: GPA: 3.8

Jan 2016-May 2017

• University of North Carolina at Charlotte

### **Bachelor of Technology in Mechanical Engineering: GPA: 3.8**

Jun 2010-May 2014

• Jawaharlal Nehru Technological University, Hyderabad, India.

## **Projects:**

### Package Tracking System: <a href="https://github.com/sreelakshmisetturu/Package-Tracking-System">https://github.com/sreelakshmisetturu/Package-Tracking-System</a>

- Built a tracking system in **Java** following MVC pattern to track the status of the package and a background simulation framework using concurrency of Java threads to update the status periodically.
- Computed shortest path for the delivery of the package between two cities by implementing Dijkstra's algorithm.

### **Restaurant Website:**

- Developed a secure Java web application for restaurants following MVC pattern for managing orders placed by customers.
- Used JSP, Servlets, JDBC, POJO, CSS3, JavaScript, Cookies, JMS to build the application.

### LZW Data Compression: https://github.com/sreelakshmisetturu/LZW-Algorithm

- Implemented fixed bit-length Lempel-Ziv-Welch compression algorithm for ASCII text in Java.
- Achieved a compression ratio of 0.38 for the sample dataset (Ratio varies based on the dataset. Higher the redundancy, lower the ratio value).

### **NYC Connect:** <a href="http://webpages.uncc.edu/nbhirud/index.html">http://webpages.uncc.edu/nbhirud/index.html</a>

- Predicted the area with more taxi demand in given time and day. Achieved 97% accuracy in predicting how much surcharge can be applied when a customer requests a taxi in given time and pick up location.
- Implemented Naïve Bayes, Logistic Regression, K means clustering algorithms in Apache Spark and Python.

#### **Chicago Crime Prediction:**

- Predicted the type of crime that can happen given an area and time in Chicago, using Logistic Regression algorithm in **Python**. Compared these results with results obtained from Artificial Neural Networks.
- Implemented K means clustering to cluster locations into Areas.

### **Achievements:**

 Received "On the spot" award for my commitment towards work as Assistant System-Engineer at Tata Consultancy Services.

• Stood as topper of the department in first year, B.tech.

July 2011